bungie.net 2012-10-24

# Bungie.net : privacy : 3/31/2012 11:15 AM PDT

The Bungie Web sites consisting of Bungie.com, Bungie.net, "7th Column" and BungieStore.com (the “Bungie Web Sites”) are operated by Bungie Inc. (“Bungie,” “we” or “us”) or its suppliers. We also provide applications for your mobile devices (“Bungie Mobile Apps”) through which we offer various services (the “Bungie Mobile Services”). Additionally, we make various online services available through our games (“Bungie Game Services”). Together, we will refer to the Bungie Mobile Services, Bungie Game Services and Bungie Web Sites as the “Bungie Services” in this Privacy Statement. This Privacy Statement applies to the Bungie Services and describes what information we collect on them, as well as how we use and disclose such information. By using the Bungie Services, you consent to the data practices described in this Privacy Statement. 

#### Collection of Information You Provide

The Bungie Services offer you the opportunity to register for an account, which permits you to use additional features offered on the Bungie Services, including Bungie Communities, Forums and the Bungie Store. Should you choose to register for an account you will be asked for personal information such as your name and e-mail address. You may also be asked for additional personal information should you choose to subscribe to newsletters, enter sweepstakes, or engage in other activities on the Bungie Services. If you use our Bungie Mobile Services, we may collect and store your phone number and location information. 

Bungie.net uses Windows Live™ ID to provide sign-in services. To create an account at Bungie.net, you must use your Windows Live ID. If you do not have a Windows Live ID, you will need to create one. To learn more about Windows Live ID, and how it uses and helps protect your personal information, please see the [Windows Live ID home page, and read the posted privacy statement there](http://www.passport.net/). 

If you are a subscriber of the Xbox Live service, your Gamertag, nicknames and statistics such as high scores may be displayed on Bungie.net and your online presence will be visible to those on your Xbox Live friends list. You will also have the opportunity to link your Xbox Live Gamertag to your Windows Live ID so that your experience can be personalized and so that you will have access to additional features. If you have already linked your Xbox Live Gamertag and your Windows Live ID on the Xbox.com Web site, Bungie.net will have access to that linkage and you will not be required to do it again. Otherwise, Bungie.net will automatically redirect and sign you in to Xbox.com in order for you to perform the linkage. Once your Gamertag and Windows Live ID have been linked, this linking may also be shared with Microsoft Corporation and other 3rd party game sites in order for those sites to provide you with a personalized experience when you sign in. For details about what information is collected by Microsoft’s Xbox Live service and how that information is used, please see the Microsoft/Xbox Live Privacy Statement at [ http://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/default.aspx](http://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/default.aspx) . 

You may connect your Bungie account with your Facebook account. To do so, you will need to give us access to the information on your Facebook account through Facebook Connect. By doing so, you authorize us to use and disclose all information exposed to us through Facebook Connect pursuant to this Privacy Statement, including your status updates, photos, videos, name, email address, information regarding your friends on Facebook, and any additional information that Facebook may make available through Facebook Connect. You should check your Facebook settings to manage the information sent to us and third parties through Facebook Connect. 

We may receive personal information and other information from third parties about you, and may combine this information with other personal information we maintain about you. If we do so, this policy also governs the combined information. 

#### Information We Collect Automatically

In addition to information that you provide to us, we collect information about your use of the Bungie Services automatically. 

On the Bungie Sites, we may collect information about your visit, including the pages and other content that you view, the links you click and other actions taken within the Bungie Site. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring Web site addresses. 

We may collect information regarding your mobile device and other information regarding your use of the Bungie Mobile Apps and Bungie Mobile Services, including your unique device ID, device type, operating system, location information, and other information as permitted by the functionality of such mobile device. 

We may collect and store information regarding your computer or device on which you play our games if you use the Bungie Game Services, such as device ID, device type and operating system, IP address, and other information as permitted by the functionality of your computer or device. 

We also may collect usability information from the Bungie Mobile Services regarding Bungie Mobile Apps, and from the Bungie Games Services regarding our various games. 

We may collect the above categories of information, and other types of information, through the use of cookies, Web beacons, logging functionality, and other technologies. Cookies and web beacons are discussed below in this Privacy Statement. 

#### Use and Disclosure of Information

We use the information we collect on the Bungie Services to operate the Bungie Services; to deliver the items and services you have requested; to enhance, improve, operate, and maintain the Bungie Services, our games, and our other systems, resources, and products; to prevent fraudulent use of the Bungie Services; to tailor your user experience, and the content and advertisements that are presented to you; to maintain a record of our dealings with you, and for other administrative purposes. 

For example: 

  * When you subscribe to communications that we provide, we use your e-mail address to send you the communications you have requested.
  * If you choose to enter your name and postal address, and indicate in your profile that you’re interested in hearing about our news and promotions, we may use that information for future mailings from us about Bungie news and promotions. 
  * We use personal information and other information that we collect to deliver customized content and advertising to users located in a particular geographic region, or whose behavior, preferences, or characteristics indicates that they may be interested in a particular subject area. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as sending newsletters, answering customer questions, fulfillment requests and performing statistical analysis of our services. We endeavor to limit the information we provide to those companies to the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. We may provide your information to Microsoft Corporation in connection with our administration of the Bungie Services and/or Bungie or Microsoft games, including without limitation, for the purpose of enforcing the Bungie Terms of Use or assisting Microsoft in enforcing its Xbox Live Terms of Use.

We may disclose your information without notice if required to do so by law or if we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) to comply with legal process served on us, or our suppliers and publishers, and otherwise when we have a good faith belief that doing so is required by law; (b) protect and defend our rights or property or those of our suppliers and publishers; (c) protect the personal safety of our employees or agents, users of Bungie products or services, or members of the public, and (d) protect the integrity of the online community on the Bungie Services and games. 

In addition, information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed in connection with a merger, acquisition, sale of our assets, or similar transaction in which another company acquires us or all or substantially all of our assets. In this event, we will notify you before personal information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy statement. 

Information that you provide on the Bungie Services or that we collect may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates, subsidiaries, suppliers, publishers or agents maintain facilities. By using the Bungie Services, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country and the use of such information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. 

#### Choice 

If you receive marketing or promotional communications from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the message that we send. If you have a Bungie account, you may unsubscribe from one or more categories of communications by logging in to your Bungie account and de-selecting those categories of communications that you no longer wish to receive. You may also opt-out from receiving marketing or promotional communications from us by sending us an email or by writing to us at the address given at the end of this policy. When you opt-out of receiving marketing or promotional communications from us, please allow up to 10 business days for your opt-out request to be processed. 

Even if you opt-out from marketing and promotional communications, you may still receive other categories of communications that you signed up to receive when creating or updating your Bungie account. 

Also, even if you opt-out from all categories of communications, you may still receive communications from us regarding your Bungie account, important updates to the Bungie Services, technical service issues, and other administrative matters pertaining to the Bungie Services. 

If your e-mail address has changed and you would like to continue to receive communications from us, you will need to sign-up again for the communications you wish to receive on the Bungie Services with your new e-mail address. 

Please be aware that this Privacy Statement and the choices you make on this site may not apply to personal information you may have provided to Microsoft in the context of other, separately operated, Microsoft products or services. 

#### Security of your Personal Information

We are committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. 

If you choose to create a profile on a Bungie Service you will be required to select a password. This password can be changed once you have logged into the service. It is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always choose to log out before leaving the Bungie Service to protect access to your personal information from subsequent users. 

Please be aware that despite our security measures, no data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. We cannot, therefore, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Bungie, and you do so at your own risk. Additionally, although we use reasonable security measures to keep your information secure, this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

If we learn of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Bungie Services or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of the Bungie Services. Bungie may post a notice on the Bungie Services if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach, or to opt out of receiving electronic notice, you should notify us at [bnetbugs@bungie.com](mailto:bnetbugs@bungie.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry). 

#### Use of Cookies

We use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to a particular device or web browser, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie. 

A primary purpose of cookies is to provide convenience and save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page, so that when you visit the site again, the experience will be personalized. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to set your computer to accept cookies from a Bungie Service, you may also be able to choose to be logged into that Bungie Service automatically, to select a country of your choice as your default home page, or to select other customized settings. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Bungie Web Sites or the other Web sites you visit. 

#### Use of Web Beacons

Web pages and other content on the Bungie Services may contain electronic images known as Web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that allow Bungie to count users who have viewed that content and to collect other statistics and information regarding the use of the Bungie Services. We do not use Web beacons to access your personal information on the Bungie Services. 

#### Communities and Forums offered on the Bungie Services

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information or personally sensitive data through Bungie Services, Bungie Communities, Forums, or other messaging functionality or social or interactive features that may be provided on the Bungie Services, this information may be collected and used by others. We recommend you be cautious in giving out personal information to others while using the Bungie Services. 

#### Windows Live™ ID

This Web site uses Windows Live ID to provide sign-in and registration services. In order to sign in to this site with Windows Live ID, you will be asked to type your e-mail address and a password. This same Windows Live ID sign-in allows you to access many other Windows Live ID participating sites and services. If you create a Windows Live ID at this site, you are simultaneously registering with the Bungie Services and creating a new Windows Live ID. All of the registration information you provide will be stored the Bungie Services, and some or all of that information will also be stored by Windows Live ID in your Windows Live ID profile with the Microsoft Corporation. To learn more about Windows Live ID, see the [Windows Live ID home page, and read the posted privacy statement there](http://www.passport.net/). 

#### Changes to this Statement

This Privacy Statement applies only to the Bungie Services and not other companies or organizations to which we may provide links from the Bungie Services. We may occasionally update this Privacy Statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by placing prominent notice on the Bungie Services. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of how we are collecting, using, and disclosing your information. 

#### Children

Bungie does not knowingly collect or retain personally identifiable information about persons under 13 years of age. Any person who provides their personal information to us through the Bungie Services represents that they are at least 13 years of age or older. If Bungie learns that personally identifiable information of persons under the age of 13 years has been collected on the Bungie Service without verifiable parental consent, then Bungie will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained a Bungie account or otherwise provided personally identifiable information to us, then you may alert us at [bnetbugs@bungie.com](mailto:bnetbugs@bungie.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry)and request that we delete that child’s personal information from its systems. 

#### Access to your personal information

If you register for a Bungie account, you may access, review, and update many categories of your personal information by logging in to your Bungie account. Additionally, you may update, correct, or delete your profile information by e-mailing us [bnetbugs@bungie.com](mailto:bnetbugs@bungie.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry). To protect your privacy and security, we may take steps to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times. 

#### Contact Information 

If you have questions or comments regarding this Privacy Statement or require additional information, please contact us. 

Bungie Privacy Bungie, Inc.  
550 106th Avenue NE  
Suite 207  
Bellevue, WA 98004-5088  

Microsoft, Windows Live, and the Windows Live and flag logo are registered trademarks of Microsoft Corporation in the United States and/or other countries.

READ FOR INFORMATION REGARDING THE BUNGIE TERMS OF USE
